Panos Tolios

full-stack developer

CONTACT

<u>(+30) 694-800-36-91</u>

panostolios@gmail.com

Kavala, Greece •

https://cv.panostolios.dev

<u>LinkedIn Profile</u> in

https://github.com/ptolios

https://gitlab.com/panostolios

EDUCATION

2011-2015

University of Macedonia, Greece

Master of Business Administration

1997-2003

Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece

Master of Engineering in Surveying Engineering

Online Courses

<u>Vue JS 2 - The Complete Guide (incl.</u> <u>Vue Router & Vuex)</u>

Platform: Udemy

Instructor: Maximilian Schwarzmüller

Certificate No: UC-ccb99c9f-2560-4fcf-b1d742c8442e140f

DESIGN RULES: Principles + Practices for Great UI Design

Platform: Udemy

Instructor: Joe Natoli

Certificate No: UC-7NV4FADR

SUMMARY

Self-motivated full-stack developer, seeking to prove skills in **Python**, **JavaScript** and **HTML/CSS**. Excellent communicator with strong problem solving, organizational and analytical skills accumulated in 15+ years of experience as an engineer. Professional, teamwork-oriented, skilled in managing self and teams. Always willing to start from scratch, enjoy learning new things, especially tech related.

SKILLS

Technical Skills Soft Skills

Programming Languages

Python

JavaScript

TypeScript

HTML/CSS

Frameworks

✓ Self-motivation

Communication

✓ Team player

✓ Organizational skills

✓ Analytical skills

✓ Problem solving

✓ Leadership

PROJECTS

Django

Vue.js

Tools

Docker

Git

Django Rest

Personal Webpage

A **responsive**, personal resume webpage written in **HTML/CSS** and **JavaScript** (no CSS or JavaScript frameworks were used).

(source code: https://github.com/ptolios/ptolios.github.io/tree/develop)

What will I cook today?

A simple, responsive recipe finder using **Vue.js**, **Vuetify** and **TypeScript** at the frontend, consuming the <u>Spoonacular</u> REST API at the backend.

(source code: https://github.com/ptolios/what-will-i-cook/tree/develop)

Backend REST API (in progress)

A **RESTful API** built in **Django Rest Framework** for the *Cutting Assistant* project, an application that will be used as an order management system and cutting optimization software.

(source code: https://gitlab.com/panostolios/cutting-assistant-backend)

EXPERIENCE

April 2014 - Present

Hellenic Cadastre Engineer - Geoapodosi SA

Engineering Consulting

- Performed cadastre related works
- Created helper scripts for CAD software
- Automated processes through software development

August 2010 - March 2014

Freelance Engineer - Self Employed

Engineering Consulting

February 2013 - February 2014

Head of Operatons Department - Douma Farm

Organic Farming & Production

- Procurement Management
- Inventory Management
- Quality Control
- Production Management
- $\hbox{-} Setup\ and\ administration\ of\ ERP\ system,\ developed\ and\ managed\ custom\ database}$

July 2009 - August 2010

Head of Surveying Department - Pagonis Dynamiki ATE

Construction Company

- Deciding on the structure and equipment of field surveying crews.
- Gathering field surveying data and verifying final bill of quantities (BOQ)
- Negotiating procedures with the customers (authorities) specifications of the project.
- Assessing performance of members of field surveying crews and report results to project manager.
- Participated/Involved in the following projects (occasionally as a project manager):
 - Municipality of Thermi Urban roads network construction
 - Municipality of Echedoros Urban roads network construction
 - Raedestos Driver's Test Track
 - Restoration of Lake Koronia

(managing 5-10 people)

May 2008 - June 2009

Co-head of Cadastral Office of Eykarpia - Makedoniki ETM

Engineering Consulting

- Responsible for the smooth operation of the Cadastral Office
- Processing of cadastral statements

(managing 3-7 people)

March 2007 - May 2008

Site Engineer - Psarras ATE

Construction Company

- Public and private infrastructure works supervision
- Participated/Involved in the following projects:
 - Sewage System of Mygdonia, Thessaloniki
 - Sewage System of Eastern Olympus, Platamon (project manager)
 - Sewage System of Lahana, Thessaloniki

(managing 5-15 people)

October 2005 - March 2007

Project Manager - Site Engineer - Aeolos ATE

Construction Company

Participated/Involved in the following projects:

- Sewage System of Agia, Larissa (project manager)
- Construction of Military Facilities, Larissa (project team)

(managing 5-20 people)

December 2003 - February 2004

Database Developer - Inter Engineering

Data Security

- Improved the company's CRM Database (using VBA for Microsoft Access)

2001 - 2003

Assistant Surveying Engineer - Poursalidis Polychronis

Surveying Engineering Office (Freelance Engineer)

- Topographic diagrams execution
- Industrial buildings, building blocks and urban road design setting out